<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-06-07T23:38:47+00:00</updated><id>https://k9chen.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal Website </subtitle><entry><title type="html">宇宙的开端仿佛是深吸一口气，然后屏住了呼吸 [CHN]</title><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi-CHN/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="宇宙的开端仿佛是深吸一口气，然后屏住了呼吸 [CHN]"/><published>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi%20-%20CHN</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi-CHN/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="暗淡蓝点">暗淡蓝点</h2> <p>这篇博格的标题出自于姜峰楠之手，一名我特别喜欢的科幻作家之一。在他的短篇小说《呼吸》中，姜峰楠表示我们人类所有的“欲望和沉思，都是这个宇宙缓缓呼出的气流”。实际上，我们每个人都是漂浮在黑暗太空中的微小星尘; 我们的宇宙就像一幅宏伟的点彩画，由无数色彩斑斓、无处不在的点组成。这些点反映着宇宙中的恒星、行星、星云和其他奇怪的星际物体，比如<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature25020">奥陌陌</a>。一般来说，认为地球是宇宙中唯一一个拥有具备技术能力的智慧生命的地方在某种程度上是有一定的可能性，而这就是<a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/66BF2364A85A6EE6FB4E8CE617899711/S1473550410000030a.pdf/div-class-title-numerical-testing-of-the-rare-earth-hypothesis-using-monte-carlo-realization-techniques-div.pdf">地球殊异假说</a>的基本论点。该假说流传已久，只可惜从主观上来讲，这个观念听起来相当荒谬。但不得不承认，目前可以用来反驳这个假说的经验性证据显而易见的有限，毕竟我们正在经历所谓的<a href="https://adsabs.harvard.edu/full/1983QJRAS..24..283B">大沉默</a>，受到了物理、时间和社会上的限制。尽管如此，我们依旧自然地倾向于思考地球外面的世界，理解不可理解的事物，并面临我们对未知事物的恐惧。即使我们的努力收效甚微，令死神望而却步的是一颗永无止境的好奇心。</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/horsehead.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> 猎户座中的马头星云。图片由<a href="https://stocksnap.io/author/srahn">史蒂芬·拉恩</a>在<a href="https://stocksnap.io">StockSnap</a>上所提供。 </div> <p>考虑到目前航天技术的进步例如<a href="https://www.nasa.gov/">美国国家航空航天局</a>和<a href="https://www.seti.org/">搜寻地外智慧生命项目</a>等组织迄今为止所做的工作，与外星人接触的可能性似乎并不像典型的关于外星人的科幻故事中描绘的那样乐观。因此，我们无法发现外星生命是<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/B9780323913607000124">费米悖论</a>的主要问题，而这个问题是由恩里科·费米在1950年与他的一群同事的午餐时间谈话中启发而来的。从那时起，甚至早在费米提出“大家都在哪儿呢”这个著名问题之前，<d-footnote>费米当时的确切言论并不清楚，因他的同事们在回忆这次谈话时写的信中的说法都各不相同，其中包括爱德华·泰勒、赫伯特·约克和埃米尔·科诺平斯基。</d-footnote>费米悖论受到了康斯坦丁·齐奥尔科夫斯基、迈克尔·哈特、弗兰克·詹宁斯·蒂普勒等天体物理学家和宇宙学家以及他们各自的支持者和批评者的仔细研究。一开始，地球之外存在外星生命的大胆猜想似乎相当苍凉。然而，鉴于我们对外星人的概率感和执着，我们的直觉告诉我们事实并非如此，正如弗兰克·德雷克提出的<a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/abs/drake-equation/introduction/90D48C581EA5B6F83F3641132989C86B">德雷克方程</a>所证明。该方程根据可探测的电磁辐射（例如无线电信号）对银河系内的外星文明数量进行了概率估计，表示为 \(N\)：</p> <p>\begin{equation} N = R_* \cdot f_p \cdot n_e \cdot f_l \cdot f_i \cdot f_c \cdot L \end{equation}</p> <p>其中 \(R_*\) 是恒星形成率，\(f_p\) 是那些恒星中拥有行星的比例，\(n_e\) 是具有合适生命环境的行星的数量，\(f_l\) 是那些具有合适生命环境的行星中能够孕育出生命的比例，\(f_i\) 是那些能够孕育出生命的行星中存在智能生命的比例，\(f_c\) 是那些拥有星际通讯技术的智慧文明的比例，最后\(L\)是此类文明可以积极维持其通讯方式的时间长度。此外，<a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/C714F4FD72D50FF029131C6E5AAB1946/S1473550417000052a.pdf/search_for_habitable_planets_with_biosignature_gases_framed_by_a_biosignature_drake_equation.pdf">西格尔方程</a>是经典德雷克方程的一个变体，<d-footnote>克劳迪奥·马康尼还提出了基于中心极限定理的经典德雷克方程的统计泛化，其中每个参数都被转化为随机变量。</d-footnote>该方程基于生物气体的检测而非电磁辐射。</p> <p>不得不说，德雷克方程也有其自身的缺陷，比方说它难以估计某些参数（例如 \(f_i\)、\(f_c\) 和 \(L\)），并且依赖于大量的数值假设，因此会产生乐观或悲观的结果；作为证明，牛津大学的一组科研团队声称我们在宇宙中独自生存的概率为<a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.02404">39–85%</a>。虽然看似令人沮丧，但它足以让我们有一定程度的信心，相信与外星人接触的可能性确实存在，无论最终计算出来的 \(N\) 的值有多小，尤其是考虑到在该模型和其他相似于德雷克方程的原始数学公式中，我们银河系规模以上的一切都被忽略了。这与<a href="https://academic.oup.com/astrogeo/article/52/5/5.33/254038">平庸原则</a>的概念一致；这就说明宇宙中存在着其他类似于地球的行星的可能性非常高。当然，话虽这么说，非典型外星环境和生命的存在也是有一定的可能性（硅基生物是一个常见的例子），因此这个猜想不能被否认。我们只能通过连接所有存在的点才能开始想象宇宙视界之外更大的图景；我们不应该孤独地存在着。</p> <h2 id="百年孤独">百年孤独</h2> <p>几十年来，针对费米悖论的各种理论解释层出不穷，这些解释要么否认外星生命的存在，要么提供解决方案来解释外星联系未发生的原因。而其中大多数都对后者怀抱着乐观的支持。一个早期的理论是<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0019103573901115">动物园假说</a>，这是由约翰·艾伦·鲍尔提出的一种社会学解释。鲍尔认为从外星生命的角度来看，地球类似于一个银河动物园，因此我们在不知情的情况下被观察，而外星文明却故意隐藏自己不并躲避我们的视线。然而，该假说存在一个严重的问题：由于<a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/0004-637X/792/1/26">单一文化谬误</a>而导致该假说站不住脚。简单来讲，要解开费米悖论，就必须制定一套规则并要求每个独立进化的外星文明都遵守，以保持动物园处于非干涉的状态（例如：严禁触摸动物）。但在没有一个预先存在的、主导的文明扮演动物园管理员角色来维持秩序的情况下，强制所有外星文明遵守这些规则在实际操作上是不太可能的，特别是在存在着大量外星文明的情况下。值得反驳的是，如果动物园里的动物在技术方面上达到了一定的成熟度，那么外星接触最终会不会发生？这在理论上是可行的，毕竟这只是个时间的问题。但由于我们现在都还不是<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-38351-y#:~:text=Humanity%20presently%20stands%20at%20Type,energy%20consumption%20models%20are%20oversimplified.">卡尔达舍夫等级</a>上的I型文明，<d-footnote>地球目前在卡尔达舍夫等级上大约处于0.7型文明；假设每年的能源消耗率为3%，地球大约需要100-200年的时间才能达到I型文明。</d-footnote>这将使我们无资格加入“<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0016328721001105">银河俱乐部</a>”。为了根据我们消耗能量的能力来衡量我们的卡尔达舍夫量级 \(K\)，卡尔·萨根利用了对数插值并提出了以下公式：</p> <p>\begin{equation} K = \frac{\log_{10}P - 6}{10} \end{equation}</p> <p>其中 \(P\) 是一个文明耗用的能量。在实际应用中，想达到 \(K = 2\) 需要大约 \(10^{26}\) 瓦的能量。如果能通过假想的巨型结构如<a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.16734.pdf">戴森球</a>和<a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.16734.pdf">俄罗斯套娃脑</a>的联合利用并从太阳般的大恒星中获取能量，这将是可行的。确实，如果一个在卡尔达舍夫等级上高度发达的文明（例如：\(K &gt; 3\)）能够从超大质量黑洞中利用暗能量并影响宇宙的膨胀速度以防止<a href="https://journals.aps.org/prd/pdf/10.1103/PhysRevD.98.104004?casa_token=6xCwTvS_VNAAAAAA%3AKLHajLEbTB0Pe0uzTFtDBXRDxEcT5RA592Va1rUBtFd102ZnF2NroS3S6OfAbUn1OEAIJvUFITEdiw">大撕裂</a>，那也不足为奇；更甚的是，这样的文明在理论上也可能在微维度尺度上操纵时空结构。<d-footnote>一个文明能够进行的向内操纵（基因、分子、夸克等）的程度与卡尔达舍夫等级使用的标准相反；时空操纵是约翰·大卫·巴罗所定义的最高级别的向内操纵。</d-footnote>因此，从目前的情况来看，我们与外星文明的接触几乎是暂时无法实现的。</p> <p>If this was not true or perhaps there are additional filters in the impending future that has yet to occur, this would be problematic for humanity because a possible Great Filter in the future could mean planetary destruction following a doomsday scenario, e.g., starving to death from a nuclear winter or getting killed by an army of <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/international-journal-of-astrobiology/article/von-neumann-probes-rationale-propulsion-interstellar-transfer-timing/5202679D74645D3707248FE5D5FA0124">von Neumann probes</a><d-footnote>The destruction of an intelligent civilization by von Neumann probes is the central idea behind the berserker hypothesis.</d-footnote> sent from extragalactic space. Either way, the point of the Great Filter is that it is an onerous task to make contact with extraterrestrial life when they cannot evolutionarily develop in a similar manner as us humans or they have already far exceeded our current evolutionary development. It has also been speculated that we are presently undergoing an <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11084-008-9149-y">astrobiological phase transition</a>–a period of disequilibrium succeeding a cataclysmic reset event, e.g., a \(\gamma\)-ray bursts impacting our galaxy, in the astrobiological time scale of the universe, in which the birth of new intelligent life has yet to arrive apart from our own civilization, henceforth making us among the first batch of intelligent life in this presumably dead universe.</p> <p>另一个旨在解决费米悖论的假说是罗宾·汉森提出的一个想法，称为<a href="https://mason.gmu.edu/~rhanson/greatfilter.html">大过滤器理论</a>。大过滤器本质上是一种时间障碍，在进化过程中的某个时间点上阻碍生命的发展，而生命起源的开始就是第一个时间点。大过滤器可能更适合被描述为某种意外事故，例如多细胞真核生物从其它们的单细胞祖先进化而来，而这毫不讽刺地花费了大约20亿年的时间，算是是一种相当罕见的现象。令我们好奇的是，人们一直在猜测大过滤器相对于我们现在的时间处于那里，以及从生命的历史上来看有多少个这样的过滤器。显然，费米悖论似乎让我们觉得人类已经成功地通过了大过滤器，而我们所谓想接触的外星生命因此可能已经被筛掉了，从而强化地球殊异假说。如果这不是真的，或者在即将到来的未来可能还会出现其他尚未发生的过滤器，那么这对人类来说将是一个巨大的问题，因为未来出现的大过滤器可能意味着世界末日情景之后的行星毁灭，例如因核冬天而饿死或被一群从河外空间发送的<a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/international-journal-of-astrobiology/article/von-neumann-probes-rationale-propulsion-interstellar-transfer-timing/5202679D74645D3707248FE5D5FA0124">冯·诺依曼探测器</a><d-footnote>一个被冯·诺依曼探测器摧毁的文明是狂战士假说中的一个示范场景。</d-footnote>杀死。无论如何，大过滤器的要点在于，当外星生命无法像我们人类一样进化发展或它们已经远远超过了我们当前的进化水平时，与外星生命取得联系是一项艰巨的任务。还有人推测我们目前正在经历一次<a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11084-008-9149-y">天体生物相变</a>；该相变在宇宙的天体生物时间尺度上是一场灾难性重置事件之后的一段不平衡时期，如伽马射线爆引起的星系分裂。在此期间，除了我们自己的文明之外，新的智慧生命尚未诞生，因此使我们成为这个假定为死寂的宇宙中首批智能生命之一。</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/bomb.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> 奥本海默眼里的由核灾难带来的世界毁灭。图片由<a href="https://pixabay.com/users/wikiimages-1897/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=63146">WikiImages</a>在<a href="https://pixabay.com//?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=63146">Pixabay</a>上所提供。 </div> <p>One other solution that is closely related to the Great Filter is explained by <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsif.2022.0029">superlinear scaling</a>. In this hypothesis, a civilization would inevitably approach a singularity in which population and energy demands cause infinite growth in a finite amount of time, effectively leading to an asympto burnout characterized by the collapse of the civilization as productivity and resource consumption scale superlinearly; this growth can be modeled by the following <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.0610172104">ODE</a>:</p> <p>一个与大过滤器理论密切相关的解决方案是通过<a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsif.2022.0029">超线性缩放</a>来解释的。根据这个假设，一个文明将不可避免地接近一个奇点，其中人口和能源需求在有限的时间内导致无限增长，从而引起一种渐近倦怠，使一个文明的生产力和资源消耗呈超线性缩放而导致该文明的衰落。</p> <p>\begin{equation} \frac{dG(t)}{dt} = \left(\frac{Y_0}{E}\right)G(t)^\beta - \left(\frac{R}{E}\right)G(t) \end{equation}</p> <p>where \(\frac{dG(t)}{dt}\) represents the rate of civilization growth with respect to time \(t\), with \(Y\) being a measure of the material resources required to sustain the civilization while \(R\) is the resources needed per capita on average, \(E\) is the resources needed, on average, for adding a new individual to the civilization, and \(\beta\) is the superlinear scaling exponent that is reflective of the general socioeconomic dynamics across the civilization, e.g., encroaching upon other worlds. In cases where \(\beta &gt; 1\), a singularity arises as the demand for resources becomes infinite in an uncontrolled population where \(G(t)\) increases in a superlinear fashion at an unprecedented exponential rate, instigating a drastic regression as the energy supply is exhausted. Given the omnipresence of the dataome, the plausibility of this hypothesis is evident in our daily lives in which our experiences are saturated with information due to the interplay among technological agents and globalization, thereby increasing the value of \(\beta\).</p> <p>To mitigate the occurrence of a singularity as a result of superlinear scaling, the parameters of the growth equation must be reset by means of innovations within the civilization to allow for a new growth trajectory; however, if \(\beta &gt; 1\) still holds true, another singularity would occur in a dreaded cycle and eventually, with time, the frequency of growth would increase in conjunction with a decrease in the time scale between innovations until the overall system collapses from an asymptomatic burnout. The point at which such burnouts occur is thus the Great Filter for humanity. Though to prevent a potential collapse necessitates a homeostatic awakening such that the civilization must come to a realization of its imminent fate prior to collapsing. In some cases, the time that is needed for such realizations to be made may precede the time of the burnout, resulting in a positive time window that can facilitate the civilization to implement systematic changes that would alter the course of its internal dynamics to favor homeostasis, such as abandoning the desire for cosmic colonialism and supremacy to reduce energy demands. Regardless of the outcomes, it is within the interest of the civilization in question to remain silent; as the proverb goes, silence is golden. Therefore, detecting extraterrestrial intelligence only becomes increasingly challenging from a remote distance, like playing hide-and-seek in a dark room, except the room is as far and wide as the universe.</p> <blockquote> <p>“我确信宇宙中充满着智慧生命。只是它们太聪明了，不会来这里。” ― 亚瑟·查理斯·克拉克</p> </blockquote> <p>Alternatively, if the search for aliens is akin to a simple game of hide-and-seek, should we consider the possibility of the aliens escaping the room to cheat the game while leaving us behind in the dark? The <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0094576511003304">transcension hypothesis</a> thinks along this line of reasoning, arguing that advanced civilizations had transcended into a computationally optimal, black hole-like “inner space” that is outside of our universe. Black holes are an ideal descriptor to illustrate such “inner spaces” due to their potential for, among many things, computing, harvesting energy, and creating a new universe–all of which are attractions that sufficiently intelligent civilizations would aspire to attain, thus compelling them to accept transcension as a developmental destiny as believed by John M. Smart. Civilizations that fail to develop into the stage of transcension thus reside in the “outer space” unless they can somehow overcome this filter; in this regard, it appears that we are far from transcension if this hypothesis was true.</p> <h2 id="黑暗森林">黑暗森林</h2> <p>The archive of possible solutions in response to the Fermi paradox is extremely extensive in terms of the existing literature, and it is not within my intention to discuss them all thoroughly herein. Though one particular solution that is of interest is provided by David Brin, wherein a civilization would annihilate another civilization to acquire the latter’s resources for its own territorial expansion in accordance with <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0040580907000676?via%3Dihub">Darwinian fitness</a>, provided that it has the technological means to do so. In the Drake equation, parameters such as \(f_i\) would thus decrease in value under such circumstances. In a universe where the amount of resources is finite, such predator-prey relations are bound to happen, and naturally, any civilization harboring the fear of annihilation by another civilization with a predatory nature would choose to make its existence unknowable, and this key notion serves as the crux of the dark forest hypothesis–alluding to the sci-fi trilogy <em>Remembrance of Earth’s Past</em> written by Liu Cixin, featuring a technologically vastly superior alien civilization called Trisolarans and their contact with Earth by means of interstellar invasion, where Earth is at risk of total annihilation by the hostile Trisolaran race after intercepting Earth’s broadcasted radio signals. As Liu elegantly explains:</p> <blockquote> <p>“The universe is a dark forest. Every civilization is an armed hunter stalking through the trees like a ghost, gently pushing aside branches that block the path and trying to tread without sound. Even breathing is done with care. The hunter has to be careful, because everywhere in the forest are stealthy hunters like him. If he finds other life–another hunter, an angel or a demon, a delicate infant or a tottering old man, a fairy or a demigod–there’s only one thing he can do: open fire and eliminate them. In this forest, hell is other people. An eternal threat that any life that exposes its own existence will be swiftly wiped out. This is the picture of cosmic civilization.”</p> </blockquote> <p>Obviously, the dark forest hypothesis does not portray the universe as a fun playground unlike some of the more optimistic interpretations to the Fermi paradox. It is therefore unwise for civilizations (like us) to broadcast signals out into space to advertise their exact location, especially taking into account the fact that our civilization cannot create something as advanced and ingenious as quantum-entangled, proton-sized sentient supercomputers with light-speed capabilities<d-footnote>In the series, these are known as sophons made from the unfolding of 11-dimensional protons into 2-dimensional sheets with a strong interaction-induced etched circuitry, after which the proton sheet is folded back into its 11-dimensional form.</d-footnote> for espionage purposes as the Trisolarans did; this idea of the universe as a dark forest shares the same motivation as the aforementioned hypotheses about remaining silent to promote survival, which could suggest the existence of a plethora of extraterrestrial civilizations and explain the lack of detectable signals from space.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/forest.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The universe as a figurative dark forest. Image by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@rosiesun?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Rosie Sun</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/photography-of-forest-1L71sPT5XKc?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>. </div> <p>Intriguingly, the Dark Forest hypothesis presents us with another paradox: It is well-aware that we may be at risk of being annihilated upon being discovered, yet we continue to engage in activities such as sending messages out into space, beginning with the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0019103575901165">Arecibo message</a> of 1974. The ethics of doings so has been heavily debated, with Stephen Hawking who once made the comparison of aliens contacting Earth to Christopher Columbus arriving at the Americas. Of course, the latter ended with a history of enslavement, bloody massacres, and viral diseases for the Native Americans. The ramifications of extraterrestrial contact can thus be easily imagined; after all, it would be a foolish idea to shout into the dark forest as if we are asking for our own demise.</p> <h2 id="饥饿游戏">饥饿游戏</h2> <p>In <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/B0080430767006057">game theory</a>, the dark forest hypothesis and the behavior of alien civilizations can be modeled via a <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2297414?seq=1">sequential game with incomplete information</a>. Let us first suppose a game involving civilizations A and B (henceforth referred to as \(C_A\) and \(C_B\), respectively) as the players, such that they are both aware of each other’s existence and are technologically capable of destroying one another; this is a scenario in which both civilizations are given complete information about each other and the game is played in its <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-540-69291-1_14#:~:text=A%20game%20in%20extensive%20form,and%20also%20occur%20in%20Chaps.">extensive form</a>. Prior to the game, two axioms are established as follows which are directly derived from Liu’s conceptualization of the dark forest:</p> <ol> <li>Survival is the primary need of civilization.</li> <li>Civilization continuously grows and expands, but the total matter in the universe remains constant.</li> </ol> <p>\(C_A\) begins the game where it can choose to either (i) destroy the other civilization or (ii) do nothing. In the case of (i), this results in a positive payoff for \(C_A\) but a negative payoff for \(C_B\); in contrast, a zero payoff is resulted in the case of (ii). If (ii) turns out to be the chosen case, it follows that \(C_B\) now has the opportunity to destroy \(C_A\) by choosing (i); otherwise, the game would continue infinitely if \(C_B\) were to choose (ii) until one of the them is destroyed by the other. By backward induction, it is thus clear that the <a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1023/A:1020945525108.pdf">subgame perfect Nash equilibrium</a> would be to have \(C_A\) destroy \(C_B\) at the first very round to prevent \(C_B\) from have a turn to destroy \(C_A\).</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/trees.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A decision tree illustrating the respective payoffs for both civilizations in a sequential game with complete information under non-Bayesian conditions. </div> <p>Now let us consider a slightly different extensive-form game that takes place in a Bayesian setting, in which both civilizations are unaware of each other’s existence and are thus provided with incomplete information to evaluate their respective payoffs which are no longer common knowledge. \(C_A\) begins the game where three choices are available: (i) destroy the other civilization (provided that their existence is known), (ii) broadcast a signal to reveal its existence, or (iii) stay silent. The only viable options for \(C_A\) are either (ii) or (iii) since it does not know the existence of \(C_B\) yet; choosing the former could put \(C_A\) at risk of being destroyed by \(C_B\), whereas the latter would guarantee \(C_A\)’s survival. The <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/002205319190155W#:~:text=Perfect%20Bayesian%20equilibrium%20and%20sequential%20equilibrium%E2%98%86&amp;text=PBE%20is%20equivalent%20to%20sequential,types%20with%20posterior%20probability%20zero.">perfect Bayesian equilibrium</a> would thus be for \(C_A\) to choose (iii) to avoid the potential outcome of being destroyed by \(C_B\). Logically, the dominant strategy to deploy in both scenarios is to follow the above axioms of the dark forest hypothesis, that is, to destroy other civilizations if practical while staying silent in regard to our whereabouts, which would ultimately lead to a <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-642-16170-4_7">Pareto-efficient</a> outcome for the winning civilization.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/decitreetwo.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A decision tree illustrating the respective payoffs for both civilizations in a sequential game with incomplete information under Bayesian conditions. </div> <h2 id="善恶之争">善恶之争</h2> <p>Suppose we are aware of the existence of an exoplanet that is more than a hundred light-years away and is inhabited by aliens that are benevolent in nature, whom are also aware of our existence; this special scenario then begs the question, would it still be justifiable to destroy the said civilization according to the dark forest hypothesis? Morally speaking, doing so would be no different than murdering your friendly neighbor. The problem with this scenario is that we have no means of knowing whether the civilization in question is benevolent or malevolent due to constraints in interstellar communication. Our inability to ascertain the true intentions of a foreign civilization can be satirically depicted as follows: Say that country X “accidentally” dropped a nuclear bomb on country Y; subsequently, the president of country Y thinks of this as a declaration of war from country X. To resolve the apparent misunderstanding, the president of country X can simply make a phone call to the president of country Y explaining how it was purely an accident, thus preventing a potential breakout of war. This would not be feasible if country Y is located on a planet that is hundreds of light-years away. A worst-case scenario would be to spend the time to gather information about the civilization of interest, only to discover that they are malevolent and are already making the first move to destroy us; with this in mind, the safest option to ensure our survival would be to destroy the said civilization notwithstanding–thereby eliminating a potential threat–before they get a chance. After all, it is plausible for them to apply the same logic to us in the event that they suspect we are a malevolent civilization; even if they were to assume we are indeed benevolent, they would nevertheless consider the possibility of us suspecting them as malevolent, which would give them a sufficient reason to destroy us to ensure their survival. To break this “<a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/48638053">chain of suspicion</a>” between any two civilizations (or among multiple civilizations), the dark forest hypothesis claims that, following natural selection, only one civilization will prevail should a sound be heard in the universe.</p> <p>While we may know nothing about the moral behavior of extraterrestrial intelligence, it does not hurt to formulate some bold ideas about their nature using our own civilization as a reference. To this date, it would be an overstatement to say our civilization is at peace given our past history and the ongoing international and domestic tensions that are due to our intolerance of others’ race, gender, politics, religion, class, etc., which are causes that would, in theory, escalate into the self-destruction of mankind as technology continues to rapidly progress while our moral compass remains stagnant in the long-run. For an extraterrestrial civilization with an even greater technological capability than us, the fact that they have yet to self-destruct implies that they must have learned to co-exist with one another peacefully in their evolutionary trajectory, such that their sense of morality is of similar magnitude as their technological development. As a matter of fact, a civilization’s societal progress toward peace ought to be assessed on the grounds of their collective moral development in lieu of their level of science and technology since peace can be attained in various ways, some of which are rather unethical. For example, peace can be established in a civilization that is under a 1984-inspired totalitarian regime in which the subjects are controlled by the ruling dictator through mind-controlling technology. Thus, a civilization that is effectively experiencing a moral stagnancy or decline is invariably prone to self-destruction, whereas a highly developed civilization is likely to continue to exist for prolonged periods of time (unless they are destroyed by external factors) as they are guided by strong moral principles.<d-footnote>One other possibility is for a civilization to have a high level of moral development but a low level of technological development; of course, such civilizations would not be vulnerable to self-destruction.</d-footnote> The latter proposition is quite reassuring for us if aliens were to ever visit Earth, in which case they are unlikely to pose as a threat as opposed to the Trisolarans, and albeit this argument is made on the basis of probability and is not self-evident in the least, it offers one possible objection to the dark forest hypothesis so as to make the desolate universe appear more tolerable and humane.</p> <blockquote> <p>“There are many ways to say I love you in this cold, dark, silent universe, as many as the twinkling stars.” ― Ken Liu</p> </blockquote> <p>Perhaps our desperate search for intelligent life in the universe may serve as a humble reminder to urge ourselves to love one another and cherish our differences for the betterment of humanity down the road. Whether or not we are alone in this vast universe, all that we need to know is the simple fact that our continual existence is a testament to our curiosity and perseverance as we mark our footprints in the history of the universe. 哦，还有最后一件事，也许你应该时不时地提醒下自己：“得以存在便是一个奇迹，能够思考就是一件乐事”。</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/sky.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The starry night sky is ever so silent yet enchanting. Image by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@grakozy?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Greg Rakozy</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/silhouette-photography-of-person-oMpAz-DN-9I?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>. </div>]]></content><author><name>陈凯文</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[我们在宇宙中是孤独的吗？外星人在哪里？他们是好是坏？等等。]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Universe Began as an Enormous Breath Being Held [ENG]</title><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi-ENG/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Universe Began as an Enormous Breath Being Held [ENG]"/><published>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi%20-%20ENG</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi-ENG/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="pale-blue-dot">Pale Blue Dot</h2> <p>The title of this blog post is attributed to Ted Chiang, a sci-fi writer whom I am particularly fond of. In his short story <em>Exhalation</em>, Chiang goes on to express that all of our “desires and ruminations are no more and no less than eddy currents generated by the gradual exhalation of our universe”. Indeed, viewing our existence from a figurative angle, all of us are simply tiny specks of stardust floating amid a dark void of space; our universe is much like a grand pointillist painting comprised of a multitude of colorful, ubiquitous dots in the form of stars, planets, nebulae, and other odd-looking astronomical objects like the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature25020">‘Oumuamua</a>. The long-established conservative belief that Earth is the only (unique) place in the universe to contain intelligent life with technological capacities–the <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/66BF2364A85A6EE6FB4E8CE617899711/S1473550410000030a.pdf/div-class-title-numerical-testing-of-the-rare-earth-hypothesis-using-monte-carlo-realization-techniques-div.pdf">Rare Earth hypothesis</a>–is quite absurd from a subjective account, albeit the apparent limited empirical evidence to refute this hypothesis ought to be acknowledged as we are currently governed by the physical, temporal, and sociological constraints of the <a href="https://adsabs.harvard.edu/full/1983QJRAS..24..283B">Great Silence</a>. Nevertheless, it is only a natural proclivity for our minds to ponder upon what is out there and to comprehend the incomprehensible as it outweighs our fear of the unknown, even if our efforts were of little to no avail, for curiosity knows no bounds.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/horsehead.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The Horsehead Nebula in the Orion constellation. Image by <a href="https://stocksnap.io/author/srahn">Stephen Rahn</a> on <a href="https://stocksnap.io">StockSnap</a>. </div> <p>Considering the current progress of spacefaring technology and the work done by organizations such as <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/">NASA</a> and <a href="https://www.seti.org/">SETI</a> thus far, the possibility of making extraterrestrial contact with aliens does not appear to be as bright as those portrayed in typical sci-fi stories about extraterrestrial intelligence. Our inability to discover extraterrestrial life is thus the principal issue of the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/B9780323913607000124">Fermi paradox</a>, a question that was inspired by Enrico Fermi in 1950 during a lunch time conversation with his fellow physicist friends. Since then, and even long before Fermi had asked the famous question of “where is everybody,”<d-footnote>Fermi's exact remarks were not clear as it was different across the letters written by his colleagues, which included Edward Teller, Herbert York, and Emil Konopinski when they recalled the conversation.</d-footnote> the Fermi paradox has been scrutinized by physicists and cosmologists such as Konstantin Tsiolkovsky, Michael H. Hart, Frank J. Tipler, and along with their respective supporters and critics. At the start, the thought of there being extraterrestrial intelligence beyond the confines of Earth seemed rather bleak. Yet, given our sense of probability and fixation with aliens, our intuition informs us otherwise, as demonstrated through the formulation of the <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/abs/drake-equation/introduction/90D48C581EA5B6F83F3641132989C86B">Drake equation</a> by Frank Drake to render a probabilistic estimation of the number of alien civilizations within the Milky Way based on detectable electromagnetic radiations, e.g., radio signals, as denoted by \(N\):</p> <p>\begin{equation} N = R_* \cdot f_p \cdot n_e \cdot f_l \cdot f_i \cdot f_c \cdot L \end{equation}</p> <p>where \(R_*\) is the rate of star formation, \(f_p\) is the fraction of those stars with planets, \(n_e\) is the number of planets with a suitable life environment, \(f_l\) is the fraction of those suitable planets that can bear life, \(f_i\) is the fraction of those life-bearing planets on which intelligent life exists, \(f_c\) is the fraction of those intelligent civilizations that possess the technology for interstellar communication, and \(L\) is the length of time such civilizations can actively maintain their method of communication. Furthermore, the <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/C714F4FD72D50FF029131C6E5AAB1946/S1473550417000052a.pdf/search_for_habitable_planets_with_biosignature_gases_framed_by_a_biosignature_drake_equation.pdf">Seager equation</a> is a variant of the classical Drake equation<d-footnote>A statistical generalization of the classical Drake equation based on the Central Limit Theorem has also been proposed by Claudio Maccone, in which each parameter is transformed into a random variable.</d-footnote> that is based on the detection of biogenic gases in lieu of electromagnetic radiations.</p> <p>Of course, the Drake equation has its own pitfalls in terms of its difficulty in estimating certain parameters (i.e., \(f_i\), \(f_c\), and \(L\)) and relying on heavy numerical assumptions, hence generating either optimistic or pessimistic results; for instance, a group of Oxford scientists claims the probability of us being alone in the universe to be <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.02404">39–85%</a>. While seemingly discouraging, it is sufficient to provide us with some degree of confidence that there is indeed a likelihood for extraterrestrial contact, regardless of how small \(N\) might turn out to be in the final analysis, especially when taking into account the fact that everything above the scale of our galaxy is ignored in the original mathematical formulation of the model and other Drake-like equations. This concurs with the <a href="https://academic.oup.com/astrogeo/article/52/5/5.33/254038">principle of mediocrity</a> wherein the odds of other Earth-like planets existing in the universe is highly likely, yet the possible existence of atypical extraterrestrial environments and life forms (e.g., silicon-based organisms) ought not to be dismissed. After all, we can only begin to visualize the bigger picture beyond the cosmological horizon by connecting all the dots there is; we are not meant to exist in solitude.</p> <h2 id="solitary-years">Solitary Years</h2> <p>For decades, various theoretical explanations have been posed to address the Fermi paradox, either denying the existence of extraterrestrial intelligence or offering solutions to explain the non-occurrence of extraterrestrial contacts, most of which have been rather optimistic in supporting the latter. One early theory is the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0019103573901115">zoo hypothesis</a>, a sociological explanation placed forward by John A. Ball asserting that from the perspective of extraterrestrial intelligence, Earth is akin to a galactic zoo such that unbeknownst to us, we are being observed while the aliens purposefully hide themselves from our eyes. One problem that the said hypothesis suffers from, however, is the <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/0004-637X/792/1/26">monocultural fallacy</a>, where, for the Fermi paradox to be dissolved, a set of rules must be in place to be adhered by every independently evolved extraterrestrial civilization to keep the zoo in a state of non-interference (e.g., Touching the animals is strictly forbidden), albeit enforcing such rules across all extraterrestrial civilizations is quite pragmatically unlikely in the absence a pre-emptive, dominant civilization to play the role of zoo keepers to keep things in check, notably when there are a large number of extraterrestrial civilizations in existence. It has also been posited that contact would ultimately occur in the event that the animals of the zoo have reached a certain level of technological maturity; this would be conceivable as it is only a matter of time, yet due to the fact that we are hardly a Type I civilization<d-footnote>Earth is presently sitting at roughly Type 0.7 on the Kardashev Scale; assuming an energy consumption rate of 3% per year, it would take roughly 100-200 years for Earth to reach Type I status.</d-footnote> on the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-38351-y#:~:text=Humanity%20presently%20stands%20at%20Type,energy%20consumption%20models%20are%20oversimplified.">Kardashev Scale</a>–making us ineligible to join the “<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0016328721001105">Galactic Club</a>”. To gauge our Kardashev type \(K\) based on our capacity to consume energy, Carl Sagan proposed the following formula utilizing logarithmic interpolation:</p> <p>\begin{equation} K = \frac{\log_{10}P - 6}{10} \end{equation}</p> <p>where \(P\) is the amount of power that a civilization uses. In application, for a civilization to achieve \(K = 2\) requires an energy of the order of \(10^{26}\) watts, which would be feasible if energy can be harnessed from a large star like the Sun through hypothetical megastructures such as the joint-utilization of <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.16734.pdf">Dyson spheres</a> and <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.16734.pdf">Matrioshka brains</a>. Indeed, it would not be a surprise if a highly developed civilization on the Kardashev Scale (i.e., \(K &gt; 3\)) is capable of harnessing dark energy from supermassive black holes and influence the expansion rate of the universe to prevent the <a href="https://journals.aps.org/prd/pdf/10.1103/PhysRevD.98.104004?casa_token=6xCwTvS_VNAAAAAA%3AKLHajLEbTB0Pe0uzTFtDBXRDxEcT5RA592Va1rUBtFd102ZnF2NroS3S6OfAbUn1OEAIJvUFITEdiw">Big Rip</a>; even more so, it is also theoretically possible for such a civilization to manipulate the fabric of space-time at the microdimensional scale.<d-footnote>The extent of inward manipulation (i.e., genes, molecules, quarks) that a civilization is capable of is opposite to the measure employed by the Kardashev Scale; space-time manipulation is the highest level of inward manipulation as defined by John D. Barrow.</d-footnote> Thus, extraterrestrial contact appears to be out of the question as of now.</p> <p>Another hypothesis that aims to resolve the Fermi paradox is an idea crafted from the minds of Robin Hanson, known as the <a href="https://mason.gmu.edu/~rhanson/greatfilter.html">Great Filter</a>, which is essentially a temporal barrier that impedes the development of life forms at some point along the evolutionary continuum, beginning with the onset of abiogenesis. The Great Filter may be better described as some kind of a freak accident, such as the evolution of multicellular eukaryotes from their unicellular ancestors, which unironically took approximately two billions years–a rather rare phenomenon. To our curiosity, it has been speculated as to where the Great Filter lies relative to our present time, as well as how many of such filters there are in the history of life. The Fermi paradox clearly made it seem as though the Great Filter had already passed for us, whereas extraterrestrial life may have been screened out, thereby reinforcing the Rare Earth hypothesis. If this was not true or perhaps there are additional filters in the impending future that has yet to occur, this would be problematic for humanity because a possible Great Filter in the future could mean planetary destruction following a doomsday scenario, e.g., starving to death from a nuclear winter or getting killed by an army of self-replicating <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/international-journal-of-astrobiology/article/von-neumann-probes-rationale-propulsion-interstellar-transfer-timing/5202679D74645D3707248FE5D5FA0124">von Neumann probes</a><d-footnote>The destruction of an intelligent civilization by von Neumann probes is the central idea behind the berserker hypothesis.</d-footnote> sent from extragalactic space. Either way, the point of the Great Filter is that it is an onerous task to make contact with extraterrestrial life when they cannot evolutionarily develop in a similar manner as us humans or they have already been wiped out from the face of the universe. It has also been speculated that we are presently undergoing an <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11084-008-9149-y">astrobiological phase transition</a>–a period of disequilibrium succeeding a cataclysmic reset event, e.g., a \(\gamma\)-ray bursts impacting our galaxy, in the astrobiological time scale of the universe, in which the birth of new intelligent life has yet to arrive apart from our own civilization, henceforth making us among the first batch of intelligent life in this presumably dead universe.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/bomb.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> An Oppenheimerian vision of world destruction from a nuclear holocaust. Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/wikiimages-1897/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=63146">WikiImages</a> on <a href="https://pixabay.com//?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=63146">Pixabay</a>. </div> <p>One other solution that is closely related to the Great Filter is explained by <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsif.2022.0029">superlinear scaling</a>. In this hypothesis, a civilization would inevitably approach a singularity in which population and energy demands would cause infinite growth in a finite amount of time, effectively leading to an asymptotic burnout characterized by the collapse of the civilization as productivity and resource consumption scale superlinearly; this growth can be modeled by the following first-order <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.0610172104">ordinary differential equation</a>:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \frac{dG(t)}{dt} = \left(\frac{Y_0}{E}\right)G(t)^\beta - \left(\frac{R}{E}\right)G(t) \end{equation}</p> <p>where \(\frac{dG(t)}{dt}\) represents the rate of civilization growth with respect to time \(t\), with \(Y\) being a measure of the material resources required to sustain the civilization while \(R\) is the resources needed per capita on average, \(E\) is the resources needed, on average, for adding a new individual to the civilization, and \(\beta\) is the superlinear scaling exponent that is reflective of the general socioeconomic dynamics across the civilization, e.g., encroaching upon other worlds. In cases where \(\beta &gt; 1\), a singularity arises as the demand for resources becomes infinite in an uncontrolled population where \(G(t)\) increases in a superlinear fashion at an unprecedented exponential rate, instigating a drastic regression as the energy supply is exhausted. Given the omnipresence of the dataome, the plausibility of this hypothesis is evident in our daily lives in which our experiences are saturated with information due to the interplay among technological agents and globalization, thereby increasing the value of \(\beta\).</p> <p>To mitigate the occurrence of a singularity as a result of superlinear scaling, the parameters of the growth equation must be reset by means of innovations within the civilization to allow for a new growth trajectory; however, if \(\beta &gt; 1\) still holds true, another singularity would occur in a dreaded cycle and eventually, with time, the frequency of growth would increase in conjunction with a decrease in the time scale between innovations until the overall system collapses from an asymptomatic burnout. The point at which such burnouts occur is thus the Great Filter for humanity. Though to prevent a potential collapse necessitates a homeostatic awakening such that the civilization must come to a realization of its imminent fate prior to collapsing. In some cases, the time that is needed for such realizations to be made may precede the time of the burnout, resulting in a positive time window that can facilitate the civilization to implement systematic changes that would alter the course of its internal dynamics to favor homeostasis, such as abandoning the desire for cosmic colonialism and supremacy to reduce energy demands. Regardless of the outcomes, it is within the interest of the civilization in question to remain silent; as the proverb goes, silence is golden. Therefore, detecting extraterrestrial intelligence only becomes increasingly challenging from a remote distance, like playing hide-and-seek in a dark room, except the room is as far and wide as the universe.</p> <blockquote> <p>“I’m sure the universe is full of intelligent life. It’s just been too intelligent to come here.” ― Arthur C. Clarke</p> </blockquote> <p>Alternatively, if the search for aliens is akin to a simple game of hide-and-seek, should we consider the possibility of the aliens escaping the room to cheat the game while leaving us behind in the dark? The <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0094576511003304">transcension hypothesis</a> thinks along this line of reasoning, arguing that advanced civilizations had transcended into a computationally optimal, black hole-like “inner space” that is outside of our universe. Black holes are an ideal descriptor to illustrate such “inner spaces” due to their potential for, among many things, computing, harvesting energy, and creating a new universe–all of which are attractions that sufficiently intelligent civilizations would aspire to attain, thus compelling them to accept transcension as a developmental destiny as believed by John M. Smart. Civilizations that fail to develop into the stage of transcension thus reside in the “outer space” unless they can somehow overcome this filter; in this regard, it appears that we are far from transcension if this hypothesis was true.</p> <h2 id="dark-forest">Dark Forest</h2> <p>The archive of possible solutions in response to the Fermi paradox is extremely extensive in terms of the existing literature, and it is not within my intention to discuss them all thoroughly herein. Though one particular solution that is of interest is provided by David Brin, wherein a civilization would annihilate another civilization to acquire the latter’s resources for its own territorial expansion in accordance with <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0040580907000676?via%3Dihub">Darwinian fitness</a>, provided that it has the technological means to do so. In the Drake equation, parameters such as \(f_i\) would thus decrease in value under such circumstances. In a universe where the amount of resources is finite, such predator-prey relations are bound to happen, and naturally, any civilization harboring the fear of annihilation by another civilization with a predatory nature would choose to make its existence unknowable, and this key notion serves as the crux of the dark forest hypothesis–alluding to the sci-fi trilogy <em>Remembrance of Earth’s Past</em> written by Liu Cixin, featuring a technologically vastly superior alien civilization called Trisolarans and their contact with Earth by means of interstellar invasion, where Earth is at risk of total annihilation by the hostile Trisolaran race after intercepting Earth’s broadcasted radio signals. As Liu elegantly explains:</p> <blockquote> <p>“The universe is a dark forest. Every civilization is an armed hunter stalking through the trees like a ghost, gently pushing aside branches that block the path and trying to tread without sound. Even breathing is done with care. The hunter has to be careful, because everywhere in the forest are stealthy hunters like him. If he finds other life–another hunter, an angel or a demon, a delicate infant or a tottering old man, a fairy or a demigod–there’s only one thing he can do: open fire and eliminate them. In this forest, hell is other people. An eternal threat that any life that exposes its own existence will be swiftly wiped out. This is the picture of cosmic civilization.”</p> </blockquote> <p>Obviously, the dark forest hypothesis does not portray the universe as a fun playground unlike some of the more optimistic interpretations to the Fermi paradox. It is therefore unwise for civilizations (like us) to broadcast signals out into space to advertise their exact location, especially taking into account the fact that our civilization cannot create something as advanced and ingenious as quantum-entangled, proton-sized sentient supercomputers with light-speed capabilities<d-footnote>In the series, these are known as sophons made from the unfolding of 11-dimensional protons into 2-dimensional sheets with a strong interaction-induced etched circuitry, after which the proton sheet is folded back into its 11-dimensional form.</d-footnote> for espionage purposes as the Trisolarans did; this idea of the universe as a dark forest shares the same motivation as the aforementioned hypotheses about remaining silent to promote survival, which could suggest the existence of a plethora of extraterrestrial civilizations and explain the lack of detectable signals from space.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/forest.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The universe as a figurative dark forest. Image by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@rosiesun?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Rosie Sun</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/photography-of-forest-1L71sPT5XKc?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>. </div> <p>Intriguingly, the Dark Forest hypothesis presents us with another paradox: It is well-aware that we may be at risk of being annihilated upon being discovered, yet we continue to engage in activities such as sending messages out into space, beginning with the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0019103575901165">Arecibo message</a> of 1974. The ethics of doings so has been heavily debated, with Stephen Hawking who once made the comparison of aliens contacting Earth to Christopher Columbus arriving at the Americas. Of course, the latter ended with a history of enslavement, bloody massacres, and viral diseases for the Native Americans. The ramifications of extraterrestrial contact can thus be easily imagined; after all, it would be a foolish idea to shout into the dark forest as if we are asking for our own demise.</p> <h2 id="hunger-games">Hunger Games</h2> <p>In <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/B0080430767006057">game theory</a>, the dark forest hypothesis and the behavior of alien civilizations can be modeled via a <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2297414?seq=1">sequential game with incomplete information</a>. Let us first suppose a game involving civilizations A and B (henceforth referred to as \(C_A\) and \(C_B\), respectively) as the players, such that they are both aware of each other’s existence and are technologically capable of destroying one another; this is a scenario in which both civilizations are given complete information about each other and the game is played in its <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-540-69291-1_14#:~:text=A%20game%20in%20extensive%20form,and%20also%20occur%20in%20Chaps.">extensive form</a>. Prior to the game, two axioms are established as follows which are directly derived from Liu’s conceptualization of the dark forest:</p> <ol> <li>Survival is the primary need of civilization.</li> <li>Civilization continuously grows and expands, but the total matter in the universe remains constant.</li> </ol> <p>\(C_A\) begins the game where it can choose to either (i) destroy the other civilization or (ii) do nothing. In the case of (i), this results in a positive payoff for \(C_A\) but a negative payoff for \(C_B\); in contrast, a zero payoff is resulted in the case of (ii). If (ii) turns out to be the chosen case, it follows that \(C_B\) now has the opportunity to destroy \(C_A\) by choosing (i); otherwise, the game would continue infinitely if \(C_B\) were to choose (ii) until one of the them is destroyed by the other. By backward induction, it is thus clear that the <a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1023/A:1020945525108.pdf">subgame perfect Nash equilibrium</a> would be to have \(C_A\) destroy \(C_B\) at the first very round to prevent \(C_B\) from have a turn to destroy \(C_A\).</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/trees.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A decision tree illustrating the respective payoffs for both civilizations in a sequential game with complete information under non-Bayesian conditions. </div> <p>Now let us consider a slightly different extensive-form game that takes place in a Bayesian setting, in which both civilizations are unaware of each other’s existence and are thus provided with incomplete information to evaluate their respective payoffs which are no longer common knowledge. \(C_A\) begins the game where three choices are available: (i) destroy the other civilization (provided that their existence is known), (ii) broadcast a signal to reveal its existence, or (iii) stay silent. The only viable options for \(C_A\) are either (ii) or (iii) since it does not know the existence of \(C_B\) yet; choosing the former could put \(C_A\) at risk of being destroyed by \(C_B\), whereas the latter would guarantee \(C_A\)’s survival. The <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/002205319190155W#:~:text=Perfect%20Bayesian%20equilibrium%20and%20sequential%20equilibrium%E2%98%86&amp;text=PBE%20is%20equivalent%20to%20sequential,types%20with%20posterior%20probability%20zero.">perfect Bayesian equilibrium</a> would thus be for \(C_A\) to choose (iii) to avoid the potential outcome of being destroyed by \(C_B\). Logically, the dominant strategy to deploy in both scenarios is to follow the above axioms of the dark forest hypothesis, that is, to destroy other civilizations if practical while staying silent in regard to our whereabouts, which would ultimately lead to a <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-642-16170-4_7">Pareto-efficient</a> outcome for the winning civilization.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/decitreetwo.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A decision tree illustrating the respective payoffs for both civilizations in a sequential game with incomplete information under Bayesian conditions. </div> <h2 id="moral-conflicts">Moral Conflicts</h2> <p>Suppose we are aware of the existence of an exoplanet that is more than a hundred light-years away and is inhabited by aliens that are benevolent in nature, whom are also aware of our existence; this special scenario then begs the question, would it still be justifiable to destroy the said civilization according to the dark forest hypothesis? Morally speaking, doing so would be no different than murdering your friendly neighbor. The problem with this scenario is that we have no means of knowing whether the civilization in question is benevolent or malevolent due to constraints in interstellar communication. Our inability to ascertain the true intentions of a foreign civilization can be ludicrously depicted as follows: Say that country \(X\) “accidentally” dropped a nuclear bomb on country \(Y\); subsequently, the president of country \(Y\) thinks of this as a declaration of war from country \(X\). To resolve the apparent misunderstanding, the president of country \(X\) can simply make a phone call to the president of country \(Y\) explaining how it was purely an accident, thus preventing a potential breakout of war. This would not be feasible if country \(Y\) is located on a planet that is hundreds of light-years away. A worst-case scenario would be to spend the time to gather information about the civilization of interest, only to discover that they are malevolent and are already making the first move to destroy us; with this in mind, the safest option to ensure our survival would be to destroy the said civilization notwithstanding–thereby eliminating a potential threat–before they get a chance. After all, it is plausible for them to apply the same logic to us in the event that they suspect we are a malevolent civilization; even if they were to assume we are indeed benevolent, they would nevertheless consider the possibility of us suspecting them as malevolent, which would give them a sufficient reason to destroy us to ensure their survival. To break this “<a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/48638053">chain of suspicion</a>” between any two civilizations (or among multiple civilizations), the dark forest hypothesis claims that, following natural selection, only one civilization will prevail should a sound be heard in the universe.</p> <p>While we may know nothing about the moral behavior of extraterrestrial intelligence, it does not hurt to formulate some bold ideas about their nature using our own civilization as a reference. To this date, it would be an overstatement to say our civilization is at peace given our past history and the ongoing international and domestic tensions that are due to our intolerance of others’ race, sexual orientation, political affiliation, religious belief, socioeconomic status, etc., which are causes that would, in theory, escalate into the self-destruction of mankind as technology continues to rapidly progress while our moral compass remains stagnant in the long-run. For an extraterrestrial civilization with an even greater technological capability than us, the fact that they have yet to self-destruct implies that they must have learned to co-exist with one another peacefully in their evolutionary trajectory, such that their sense of morality is of similar magnitude as their technological development. As a matter of fact, a civilization’s societal progress toward peace ought to be assessed on the grounds of their collective moral development in lieu of their level of science and technology since peace can be attained in various ways, some of which are rather unethical. For example, peace can be established in a civilization that is under a 1984-inspired totalitarian regime in which the subjects are controlled by the ruling dictator through mind-controlling technology. Thus, a civilization that is effectively experiencing a moral stagnancy or decline is invariably prone to self-destruction, whereas a highly developed civilization is likely to continue to exist for prolonged periods of time (unless they are destroyed by external factors) as they are guided by strong moral principles.<d-footnote>One other possibility is for a civilization to have a high level of moral development but a low level of technological development; of course, such civilizations would not be vulnerable to self-destruction.</d-footnote> The latter proposition is quite reassuring for us if aliens were to ever visit Earth, in which case they are unlikely to pose as a threat as opposed to the Trisolarans, and albeit this argument is made on the basis of probability and is not self-evident in the least, it offers one possible objection to the dark forest hypothesis so as to make the desolate universe appear more tolerable and humane.</p> <blockquote> <p>“There are many ways to say I love you in this cold, dark, silent universe, as many as the twinkling stars.” ― Ken Liu</p> </blockquote> <p>Perhaps our desperate search for intelligent life in the universe may serve as a humble reminder to urge ourselves to love one another and cherish our differences for the betterment of humanity down the road. Whether or not we are alone in this vast universe, all that we need to know is the simple fact that our continual existence is a testament to our curiosity and perseverance as we mark our footprints in the history of the universe. Oh, and one last thing, and perhaps something that you should be reminded of from time to time: “Contemplate the marvel that is existence, and rejoice that you are able to do so”.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/sky.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> The starry night sky is ever so silent yet enchanting. Image by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@grakozy?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Greg Rakozy</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/silhouette-photography-of-person-oMpAz-DN-9I?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash">Unsplash</a>. </div>]]></content><author><name>Kelvin Chen</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are we alone in the universe? Where are the aliens? Are they good or evil? Etc.]]></summary></entry></feed>