<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-07-05T21:35:51+00:00</updated><id>https://k9chen.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal Website </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ch2. Descartes’ Last Words, Poignantly Expressed as a Cardioid</title><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/descartes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ch2. Descartes’ Last Words, Poignantly Expressed as a Cardioid"/><published>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/descartes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/descartes/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="star-crossed-lovers">Star-Crossed Lovers</h2> <p>Many know René Descartes for his intellectual pursuits, among which are his philosophical ideas regarding the mind, i.e. mind-body dualism, and co-pioneering the field of analytic geometry in the early to mid-17th century. Yet there is an unpopularized story about the romance shared between Descartes and Princess Christina, a member of the House of Vasa who would eventually become the Queen of Sweden. For context, Descartes was originally a Frenchman but sought refuge in Sweden in an attempt to escape persecution from the Louise royal family of the House of Bourbon. There, Descartes had no luck in finding a proper job due to his perceived status as a fugitive, but he continued to pursue his mathematical endeavors nevertheless. This thus serves as the premise of Descartes’ love story, a story that has manifested itself as a representation of one of Descartes’ many prominent contributions to mathematics. Hence, the story unfolded in the following manner, with some minor details omitted for the sake of brevity:</p> <h3 id="act-i">Act I</h3> <p>On one afternoon, perhaps it was due to pure coincidence or fate, Descartes was sitting on the streets of Stockholm indulging in his analytical studies when a carriage appeared in front of him; inside was the distinguished, young Princess Christina of Sweden, who had an interest in mathematics and inquired Descartes about his work with great respect and admiration. In turn, Descartes, who was initially unaware of the girl that stood before him, took notice of the princess’ potential for mathematics. The princess eventually departed as Descartes returned to his studies in the ensuing days.</p> <h3 id="act-ii">Act II</h3> <p>Following Descartes’ first encounter with the princess, he was soon appointed to the royal court as Princess Christina’s mathematics teacher on the order of the king. As a sign of his gratitude, Descartes dedicated himself to teaching the princess his wealth of mathematical knowledge, including the Cartesian coordinate system which reconciled the relationship between algebraic formulations and geometric curves. The time that the two had spent together not only saw an improvement in Princess Christina’s mathematics abilities, but there also appears to be a much deeper connection between the two, partially due to the princess’ admiration toward Descartes’ talent, and they quickly realized it was a pure sense of love that had sprouted while paying no mind to their drastic differences in social standing and age (\(&gt; 30\) years). The king, however, quickly became informed about the love affair between his daughter and Descartes as words spread like wildfire.</p> <h3 id="act-iii">Act III</h3> <p>Infuriated, the king had ordered Descartes to be arrested and imprisoned. Saddened by the news, Princess Christina took the courage to rescue her lover from prison despite Descartes’ wish to not burden and implicate the princess, so that they could elope to England. Yet in the end, all efforts were to no avail. The king ultimately exiled Descartes to his home country, thereby separating the love ties between Descartes and the princess. Prior to his departure, Descartes gave the princess one final lesson, holding back his tears as he taught Princess Christina what he perceives to be the most beautiful analytical expression there is.</p> <h3 id="act-iv">Act IV</h3> <p>Descartes was able to safely return back to Paris after a new king had ascended to rule over the Kingdom of France, who graciously granted amnesty to fugitives. Unfortunately, Descartes had shortly fallen ill due to the presence of the Black Death that was plaguing Europe. Notwithstanding his struggle against his illness, Descartes would constantly dream about Princess Christina, as she was the only reason for his desire to keep on living besides pursuing mathematics. And thus, out of affection, Descartes wrote letters to the princess from time to time in spite of not having received any replies, and it was only a matter of time before death met Descartes at the door. Yet unbeknown to Descartes, all of his letters to the princess had been intercepted by the king upon arriving to Stockholm. In his last moments, Descartes wrote one final letter to the princess, marking it to be the 13th letter. After resting his pen and dwelling on the thought of being with Princess Christina, Descartes breathed his last breath on a cold winter day.</p> <h3 id="act-v">Act V</h3> <p>When Descartes’ 13th letter was intercepted by the king as usual, it only contained a mathematical expression that had perplexed him. After summoning a handful of mathematicians to decipher the meaning of this strange letter, no one was able to solve the expression, and thereafter the king gave the letter to Princess Christina, who was placed under house arrest at the time. Recalling Descartes’ last lesson to her, the princess was able to understand the meaning of the letter only to found her heart shattered in broken pieces; it was a confession from Descartes:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \ r = a (1 - \sin \theta) <br/> \end{equation}</p> <p>On the Cartesian coordinate plane, this expression rendered a perfect heart-shaped curve known as a cardioid, representing Descartes’ wholehearted love toward Princess Christina even in his death.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/queen.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> An oil painting titled Dispute of Queen Cristina Vasa and Rene Descartes by Nils Forsberg after Pierre-Louis Dumesnil the Younger (<a href="https://hekint.org/2024/03/28/rene-descartes-found-that-sweden-was-hazardous-to-his-health/">Image Source</a>). </div> <p>The story of Descartes and Princess Christina was truly a classic tale.<d-footnote>One disclaimer is that this story is not, in fact, historically accurate; for example, when Descartes first met Christina in Sweden, she was already the queen of the Swedish Empire and instead of mathematics, Descartes taught her philosophy but shortly died of pneumonia. Furthermore, there were never any hints of love between the two; rather, it was quite the opposite in truth.</d-footnote> Despite not conforming to traditional literary tropes in a fairy tale, i.e. having a ‘happily ever after’ ending, the story concluded with us knowing that even in his state of misery and failings, Descartes died happy as he gripped onto his immense love for the princess, a fate that is incidentally analogous to that of the little match girl. It could be said that given these circumstances, Descartes is a pessimistic romanticist due to the pervasive sense of Schopenhauerian melancholy that has manifested as a deep-seated nostalgia for the past or an acute awareness of the transient nature of one’s source of joy and fulfillment. The hopes and dreams of Descartes thus lie profound moments of beauty, but also intense feelings of sorrow and despair that had to be accepted. In the end, one must imagine Descartes happy.</p> <p><em>Note:</em> Thumbnail Image Source: <a href="https://xkcd.com/152/">xkcd</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kelvin Chen</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The happy or perhaps sad love story of a beloved thinker from history.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ch1. The Universe Began as an Enormous Breath Being Held</title><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ch1. The Universe Began as an Enormous Breath Being Held"/><published>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2024/fermi/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="pale-blue-dot">Pale Blue Dot</h2> <p>The title of this blog post is a brief excerpt from <em>Exhalation</em> written by Ted Chiang, a sci-fi writer whom I am particularly fond of. In this short story, Chiang goes on to express that all of our “desires and ruminations are no more and no less than eddy currents generated by the gradual exhalation of our universe”. Indeed, viewing our existence from a figurative angle, all of us are simply tiny specks of stardust floating amid a dark void of space; our universe is much like a grand pointillist painting comprised of a multitude of colorful, ubiquitous dots in the form of stars, planets, nebulae, and other odd-looking astronomical objects like the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nature25020">‘Oumuamua</a>. That said, the long-established conservative belief that Earth is the only (unique) place in the universe to contain intelligent life with technological capacities–the <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/66BF2364A85A6EE6FB4E8CE617899711/S1473550410000030a.pdf/div-class-title-numerical-testing-of-the-rare-earth-hypothesis-using-monte-carlo-realization-techniques-div.pdf">Rare Earth hypothesis</a>–is quite absurd from a subjective account, albeit the apparent limited empirical evidence to refute this hypothesis ought to be acknowledged as we are currently governed by the physical, temporal, and sociological constraints of the <a href="https://adsabs.harvard.edu/full/1983QJRAS..24..283B">Great Silence</a>. Nevertheless, it is only a natural proclivity for our minds to ponder upon what is out there and to comprehend the incomprehensible as it outweighs our fear of the unknown, even if our efforts were of little to no avail, for curiosity knows no bounds.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/nasa.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> An image captured by the James Webb Space Telescope depicting the edge of a giant, gaseous cavity within NGC 3324 in the Carina Nebula, an image that virtually everyone set it as their new wallpaper (<a href="https://science.nasa.gov/mission/webb/multimedia/images/">Image Source</a>). </div> <p>Considering the current progress of spacefaring technology and the work done by organizations such as <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/">NASA</a> and <a href="https://www.seti.org/">SETI</a> thus far, the possibility of making extraterrestrial contact with aliens does not appear to be as bright as those portrayed in typical sci-fi stories about extraterrestrial intelligence. Our inability to discover extraterrestrial life is thus the principal issue of the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/B9780323913607000124">Fermi paradox</a>, a question that was inspired by Enrico Fermi in 1950 during a lunch time conversation with his fellow physicist friends. Since then, and even long before Fermi had asked the famous question of “where is everybody,”<d-footnote>Fermi's exact remarks were not clear as it was different across the letters written by his colleagues, which included Edward Teller, Herbert York, and Emil Konopinski when they recalled the conversation.</d-footnote> the Fermi paradox has been scrutinized by physicists and cosmologists such as Konstantin Tsiolkovsky, Michael H. Hart, Frank J. Tipler, and along with their respective supporters and critics. At the start, the thought of there being extraterrestrial intelligence beyond the confines of Earth seemed rather bleak. Yet, given our sense of probability and fixation with aliens, our intuition informs us otherwise, as demonstrated through the formulation of the <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/abs/drake-equation/introduction/90D48C581EA5B6F83F3641132989C86B">Drake equation</a> by Frank Drake to render a probabilistic estimation of the number of alien civilizations within the Milky Way based on detectable electromagnetic radiations, e.g. radio signals, as denoted by \(N\):</p> <p>\begin{equation} N = R_* \cdot f_p \cdot n_e \cdot f_l \cdot f_i \cdot f_c \cdot L \end{equation}</p> <p>where \(R_*\) is the rate of star formation, \(f_p\) is the fraction of those stars with planets, \(n_e\) is the number of planets with a suitable life environment, \(f_l\) is the fraction of those suitable planets that can bear life, \(f_i\) is the fraction of those life-bearing planets on which intelligent life exists, \(f_c\) is the fraction of those intelligent civilizations that possess the technology for interstellar communication, and \(L\) is the length of time such civilizations can actively maintain their method of communication. Furthermore, the <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/services/aop-cambridge-core/content/view/C714F4FD72D50FF029131C6E5AAB1946/S1473550417000052a.pdf/search_for_habitable_planets_with_biosignature_gases_framed_by_a_biosignature_drake_equation.pdf">Seager equation</a> is a variant of the classical Drake equation that is based on the detection of biogenic gases in lieu of electromagnetic radiations.<d-footnote>A statistical generalization of the classical Drake equation based on the Central Limit Theorem has also been proposed by Claudio Maccone, in which each parameter is transformed into a random variable.</d-footnote></p> <p>Of course, the Drake equation has its own pitfalls in terms of its difficulty in estimating certain parameters, i.e., \(f_i\), \(f_c\), and \(L\), and relying on heavy numerical assumptions, hence generating either optimistic or pessimistic results; for instance, a group of Oxford scientists claims the probability of us being alone in the universe to be <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.02404">39–85%</a>. While seemingly discouraging, it is sufficient to provide us with some degree of confidence that there is indeed a likelihood for extraterrestrial contact, regardless of how small \(N\) might turn out to be in the final analysis, especially when taking into account the fact that everything above the scale of our galaxy is ignored in the original mathematical formulation of the model and other Drake-like equations. This concurs with the <a href="https://academic.oup.com/astrogeo/article/52/5/5.33/254038">principle of mediocrity</a> wherein the odds of other Earth-like planets existing in the universe is highly likely, yet the possible existence of atypical extraterrestrial environments and life forms, e.g. silicon-based organisms, ought not to be dismissed. After all, we can only begin to visualize the bigger picture beyond the cosmological horizon by connecting all the dots there is; we are not meant to exist in solitude.</p> <h2 id="solitary-years">Solitary Years</h2> <p>For decades, various theoretical explanations have been posed to address the Fermi paradox, either denying the existence of extraterrestrial intelligence or offering solutions to explain the non-occurrence of extraterrestrial contacts, most of which have been rather optimistic in supporting the latter. One early theory is the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0019103573901115">zoo hypothesis</a>, a sociological explanation placed forward by John A. Ball asserting that from the perspective of extraterrestrial intelligence, Earth is akin to a galactic zoo such that unbeknownst to us, we are being observed while the aliens purposefully hide themselves from our eyes. One problem that the said hypothesis suffers from, however, is the <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/0004-637X/792/1/26">monocultural fallacy</a>, where, for the Fermi paradox to be dissolved, a set of rules must be in place to be adhered by every independently evolved extraterrestrial civilization to keep the zoo in a state of non-interference, i.e. touching the animals is strictly forbidden. However, enforcing such rules across all extraterrestrial civilizations is quite pragmatically unlikely in the absence a pre-emptive, dominant civilization to play the role of zoo keepers to keep things in check, notably when there are a large number of extraterrestrial civilizations in existence. It has also been posited that contact would ultimately occur in the event that the animals of the zoo have reached a certain level of technological maturity; this would be conceivable as it is only a matter of time, yet due to the fact that we are hardly a Type I civilization on the <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-023-38351-y#:~:text=Humanity%20presently%20stands%20at%20Type,energy%20consumption%20models%20are%20oversimplified.">Kardashev Scale</a>–making us ineligible to join the “<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0016328721001105">Galactic Club</a>.”<d-footnote>Earth is presently sitting at roughly Type 0.7 on the Kardashev Scale; assuming an energy consumption rate of 3% per year, it would take roughly 100-200 years for Earth to reach Type I status.</d-footnote> To gauge our Kardashev type \(K\) based on our capacity to consume energy, Carl Sagan proposed the following formula utilizing logarithmic interpolation:</p> <p>\begin{equation} K = \frac{\log_{10}P - 6}{10} \end{equation}</p> <p>where \(P\) is the amount of power that a civilization uses. In application, for a civilization to achieve \(K = 2\) requires an energy of the order of \(10^{26}\) watts, which would be feasible if energy can be harnessed from a large star like the Sun through hypothetical megastructures such as the joint-utilization of <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.16734.pdf">Dyson spheres</a> and <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2006.16734.pdf">Matrioshka brains</a>. Indeed, it would not be a surprise if a highly developed civilization on the Kardashev Scale, i.e. \(K &gt; 3\), is capable of harnessing dark energy from supermassive black holes and influence the expansion rate of the universe to prevent the <a href="https://journals.aps.org/prd/pdf/10.1103/PhysRevD.98.104004?casa_token=6xCwTvS_VNAAAAAA%3AKLHajLEbTB0Pe0uzTFtDBXRDxEcT5RA592Va1rUBtFd102ZnF2NroS3S6OfAbUn1OEAIJvUFITEdiw">Big Rip</a>; even more so, it is also theoretically possible for such a civilization to manipulate the fabric of space-time at the microdimensional scale.<d-footnote>The extent of inward manipulation, e.g., genes, molecules, and quarks, that a civilization is capable of is opposite to the measure employed by the Kardashev Scale; space-time manipulation is the highest level of inward manipulation as defined by John D. Barrow.</d-footnote> Thus, extraterrestrial contact appears to be out of the question as of now.</p> <p>Another hypothesis that aims to resolve the Fermi paradox is an idea crafted from the minds of Robin Hanson, known as the <a href="https://mason.gmu.edu/~rhanson/greatfilter.html">Great Filter</a>, which is essentially a temporal barrier that impedes the development of life forms at some point along the evolutionary continuum, beginning with the onset of abiogenesis. The Great Filter may be better described as some kind of a freak accident, such as the evolution of multicellular eukaryotes from their unicellular ancestors, which unironically took approximately two billions years–a rather rare phenomenon. To our curiosity, it has been speculated as to where the Great Filter lies relative to our present time, as well as how many of such filters there are in the history of life. The Fermi paradox clearly made it seem as though the Great Filter had already passed for us, whereas extraterrestrial life may have been screened out, thereby reinforcing the Rare Earth hypothesis. If this was not true or perhaps there are additional filters in the impending future that has yet to occur, this would be problematic for humanity because a possible Great Filter in the future could mean planetary destruction following a doomsday scenario, i.e. starving to death from a nuclear winter or getting killed by an army of self-replicating <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/international-journal-of-astrobiology/article/von-neumann-probes-rationale-propulsion-interstellar-transfer-timing/5202679D74645D3707248FE5D5FA0124">von Neumann probes</a> sent from extragalactic space.<d-footnote>The destruction of an intelligent civilization by von Neumann probes is the central idea behind the berserker hypothesis.</d-footnote> Either way, the point of the Great Filter is that it is an onerous task to make contact with extraterrestrial life when they cannot evolutionarily develop in a similar manner as us humans or they have already been wiped out from the face of the universe. It has also been speculated that we are presently undergoing an <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11084-008-9149-y">astrobiological phase transition</a>–a period of disequilibrium succeeding a cataclysmic reset event, e.g. a gamma-ray burst impacting our galaxy, in the astrobiological time scale of the universe, in which the birth of new intelligent life has yet to arrive apart from our own civilization, henceforth making us among the first batch of intelligent life in this presumably dead universe.</p> <h2 id="singularity">Singularity</h2> <p>One other solution that is closely related to the Great Filter is explained by <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsif.2022.0029">superlinear scaling</a>. In this hypothesis, a civilization would inevitably approach a <a href="https://cmm.cenart.gob.mx/delanda/textos/tech_sing.pdf">singularity</a> in which population and energy demands would cause infinite growth in a finite amount of time, effectively leading to an asymptotic burnout characterized by the collapse of the civilization as productivity and resource consumption scale superlinearly; this growth can be modeled by the following first-order <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.0610172104">ordinary differential equation</a>:</p> <p>\begin{equation} \frac{dG(t)}{dt} = \left(\frac{Y_0}{E}\right)G(t)^\beta - \left(\frac{R}{E}\right)G(t) \end{equation}</p> <p>where \(\frac{dG(t)}{dt}\) represents the rate of civilization growth with respect to time \(t\), with \(Y\) being a measure of the material resources required to sustain the civilization while \(R\) is the resources needed per capita on average, \(E\) is the resources needed, on average, for adding a new individual to the civilization, and \(\beta\) is the superlinear scaling exponent that is reflective of the general socioeconomic dynamics across the civilization, i.e. encroaching upon other worlds. In cases where \(\beta &gt; 1\), a singularity arises as the demand for resources becomes infinite in an uncontrolled population where the function \(G(t)\) increases in a superlinear fashion at an unprecedented exponential rate, instigating a drastic regression as the energy supply is exhausted. Given the omnipresence of the dataome, the plausibility of this hypothesis is evident in our daily lives in which our lived experiences are saturated with information due to globalization and the interplay among technological agents, thereby increasing the value of \(\beta\) to eventually become greater than \(1\).</p> <p>To mitigate the occurrence of a singularity as a result of superlinear scaling, the parameters of the growth equation must be reset by means of innovations within the civilization to allow for a new growth trajectory; however, if \(\beta &gt; 1\) still holds true, another singularity would occur in a dreaded cycle and eventually, with time, the frequency of growth would increase in conjunction with a decrease in the time scale between innovations until the overall system collapses from an asymptomatic burnout. The point at which such burnouts occur is thus the Great Filter for humanity. Though to prevent a potential collapse necessitates a homeostatic awakening such that the civilization must come to a realization of its imminent fate prior to collapsing. In some cases, the time that is needed for such realizations to be made may precede the time of the burnout, resulting in a positive time window that can facilitate the civilization to implement systematic changes that would alter the course of its internal dynamics to favor homeostasis, such as abandoning the desire for cosmic colonialism and supremacy to reduce energy demands. Regardless of the outcomes, it is within the interest of the civilization in question to remain silent; as the proverb goes, silence is golden. Therefore, detecting extraterrestrial intelligence only becomes increasingly challenging from a remote distance, like playing hide-and-seek in a dark room, except the room is as far and wide as the universe.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/sing.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A simple graph showing the imminent progress toward the singularity as human intelligence advances facilitated by AI (<a href="https://www.matec-conferences.org/articles/matecconf/pdf/2019/39/matecconf_mse2019_12014.pdf">Image Source</a>). </div> <p>Alternatively, if the search for aliens is akin to a simple game of hide-and-seek, should we consider the possibility of the aliens escaping the room to cheat the game while leaving us behind in the dark? The <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0094576511003304">transcension hypothesis</a> thinks along this line of reasoning, arguing that advanced civilizations had transcended into a computationally optimal, black hole-like “inner space” that is outside of our universe. Black holes are an ideal descriptor to illustrate such “inner spaces” due to their potential for, among many things, computing, harvesting energy, and creating a new universe–all of which are attractions that sufficiently intelligent civilizations would aspire to attain, thus compelling them to accept transcension as a developmental destiny as believed by John M. Smart. Civilizations that fail to develop into the stage of transcension thus reside in the “outer space” unless they can somehow overcome this filter; in this regard, it appears that we are far from transcension if this hypothesis was true.</p> <h2 id="dark-forest">Dark Forest</h2> <p>The archive of possible solutions in response to the Fermi paradox is extremely extensive in terms of the existing literature, and it is not within my intention to discuss them all thoroughly herein. Though one particular solution that is of interest is provided by David Brin, wherein a civilization would annihilate another civilization to acquire the latter’s resources for its own territorial expansion in accordance with <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0040580907000676?via%3Dihub">Darwinian fitness</a>, provided that it has the technological capacity to do so and that the targeted civilization is technologically inferior. In the Drake equation, parameters such as \(f_i\) would thus decrease in value under such circumstances. In a universe where the amount of resources is finite, such predator-prey relations are bound to occur, and naturally, any civilization harboring the fear of annihilation by another civilization with a predatory nature would choose to make its existence unknowable to avoid the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0265964623000486">Hobbesian trap</a> in lieu of making a fear-induced pre-emptive attack, and this key notion serves as the crux of the <a href="https://academic.oup.com/monist/article/107/2/176/7629691">dark forest hypothesis</a>–alluding to the sci-fi trilogy <em>Remembrance of Earth’s Past</em> written by Cixin Liu, featuring a technologically advanced alien civilization called Trisolarans from Alpha Centauri and their contact with Earth by means of interstellar invasion, where Earth is at risk of total annihilation by the hostile Trisolaran race after intercepting Earth’s broadcasted radio signals. In regard to the dark forest hypothesis, Liu meticulously explains in the following manner:</p> <blockquote> <p>“The universe is a dark forest. Every civilization is an armed hunter stalking through the trees like a ghost, gently pushing aside branches that block the path and trying to tread without sound. Even breathing is done with care. The hunter has to be careful, because everywhere in the forest are stealthy hunters like him. If he finds other life–another hunter, an angel or a demon, a delicate infant or a tottering old man, a fairy or a demigod–there’s only one thing he can do: open fire and eliminate them. In this forest, hell is other people. An eternal threat that any life that exposes its own existence will be swiftly wiped out. This is the picture of cosmic civilization.”</p> </blockquote> <p>Obviously, the dark forest hypothesis does not portray the universe as a fun playground unlike some of the more optimistic interpretations to the Fermi paradox. It is therefore unwise for civilizations (like us) to broadcast signals out into space to advertise their exact location, especially taking into account the fact that our civilization cannot create something as advanced and ingenious as quantum-entangled, proton-sized sentient supercomputers with light-speed capabilities for espionage purposes as the Trisolarans did;<d-footnote>In the series, these are known as sophons made from the unfolding of 11-dimensional protons into 2-dimensional sheets with a strong interaction-induced etched circuitry, after which the proton sheet is folded back into its 11-dimensional form.</d-footnote> this idea of the universe as a dark forest shares the same motivation as the aforementioned hypotheses about remaining silent to promote survival, which could suggest the existence of a plethora of extraterrestrial civilizations and explain the lack of detectable signals from space.</p> <p>Intriguingly, the dark forest hypothesis presents us with another paradox: It is well-aware that we may be at risk of being annihilated upon being discovered, yet we continue to engage in sending messages out into space, as seen with the <a href="https://dbpedia.org/page/Morse_Message_(1962)">Morse message</a> of 1962 and the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0019103575901165">Arecibo message</a> of 1974 sent by Soviet and U.S. scientists, respectively. The ethics of doings so has been heavily deliberated, with Stephen Hawking who once made the comparison of aliens contacting Earth to Christopher Columbus arriving in the Americas. Of course, the latter ended with a history of enslavement, bloody massacres, and viral diseases for the Native Americans. The ramifications of extraterrestrial contact can thus be easily imagined; after all, it would be a foolish idea to shout into the dark forest as if we are asking for our own demise, a place where there is not enough meat to feed the wolves.</p> <h2 id="hunger-games">Hunger Games</h2> <p>By means of <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/B0080430767006057">game theory</a>, the dark forest hypothesis and the behavior of alien civilizations can be modeled via a <a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/2297414?seq=1">sequential game with incomplete information</a>. Let us first suppose a game involving civilizations \(A\) and \(B\) (henceforth referred to as \(C_A\) and \(C_B\), respectively) as the players, such that they are both aware of each other’s existence and are technologically capable of destroying one another; this is a <a href="https://www.jair.org/index.php/jair/article/view/10197">non-Bayesian game</a> in which both civilizations are given complete information about each other and the game is played in <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-540-69291-1_14#:~:text=A%20game%20in%20extensive%20form,and%20also%20occur%20in%20Chaps.">extensive form</a>. Prior to the game, two axioms are established as follows which are directly derived from Liu’s conceptualization of the dark forest:</p> <ol> <li>Survival is the primary need of civilization.</li> <li>Civilization continuously grows and expands, but the total matter in the universe remains constant.</li> </ol> <p>\(C_A\) begins the game where it can choose to either (i) destroy the other civilization or (ii) do nothing. In the case of (i), this results in a positive payoff for \(C_A\) but a negative payoff for \(C_B\); in contrast, a zero payoff is resulted in the case of (ii). If (ii) turns out to be the chosen case, it follows that \(C_B\) now has the opportunity to destroy \(C_A\) by choosing (i); otherwise, the game would continue infinitely if \(C_B\) were to choose (ii) until one of the them is destroyed by the other. By backward induction, it is thus clear that the <a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1023/A:1020945525108.pdf">subgame perfect Nash equilibrium</a> would be to have \(C_A\) destroy \(C_B\) at the very first round of the game to prevent \(C_B\) from having a turn to destroy \(C_A\).</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/trees.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A decision tree illustrating the respective payoffs for both civilizations in a sequential game with complete information under non-Bayesian conditions. </div> <p>Now let us consider a slightly different extensive-form game that takes place under Bayesian conditions, in which both civilizations are unaware of each other’s existence and are thus provided with incomplete information to evaluate their respective payoffs which are no longer common knowledge. \(C_A\) begins the game where three choices are available: (i) destroy the other civilization (provided that their existence is known), (ii) broadcast a signal to reveal its existence, or (iii) stay silent. The only viable options for \(C_A\) are either (ii) or (iii) since it does not know the existence of \(C_B\) yet; choosing the former could put \(C_A\) at risk of being destroyed by \(C_B\), whereas the latter would guarantee \(C_A\)’s survival. The <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/002205319190155W#:~:text=Perfect%20Bayesian%20equilibrium%20and%20sequential%20equilibrium%E2%98%86&amp;text=PBE%20is%20equivalent%20to%20sequential,types%20with%20posterior%20probability%20zero.">perfect Bayesian equilibrium</a> would thus be for \(C_A\) to choose (iii) to avoid the potential outcome of being destroyed by \(C_B\). Logically, the dominant strategy to deploy in both scenarios is to follow the above axioms of the dark forest hypothesis, that is, to destroy other civilizations if practical while staying silent in regard to our whereabouts, which would ultimately lead to a <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-642-16170-4_7">Pareto-efficient</a> outcome for the winning civilization, otherwise the game would lead to a <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/104346399011002002">catch-22</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/decitreetwo.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A decision tree illustrating the respective payoffs for both civilizations in a sequential game with incomplete information under Bayesian conditions. </div> <h2 id="moral-inquiry">Moral Inquiry</h2> <p>Suppose we are aware of the existence of an exoplanet that is more than a hundred light-years away and is inhabited by aliens that are benevolent in nature, whom are also aware of our existence; this special scenario then begs the question, would it still be justifiable to destroy the said civilization according to the dark forest hypothesis? Morally speaking, doing so would be no different than murdering your friendly neighbor. The problem with this scenario is that we have no means of knowing whether the civilization in question is benevolent or malevolent due to constraints in interstellar communication. Our inability to ascertain the true intentions of a foreign civilization can be ludicrously depicted as follows: Say that country \(X\) “accidentally” dropped a nuclear bomb on country \(Y\); subsequently, the president of country \(Y\) thinks of this as a declaration of war from country \(X\). To resolve the apparent misunderstanding, the president of country \(X\) can simply make a phone call to the president of country \(Y\) explaining how it was purely an accident, thus preventing a potential breakout of war. This would not be feasible if country \(Y\) is located on a planet that is hundreds of light-years away. A worst-case scenario would be to spend the time to gather information about the civilization of interest, only to discover that they are malevolent and are already making the first move to destroy us; with this in mind, the safest option to ensure our survival would be to destroy the said civilization notwithstanding–thereby eliminating a potential threat–before they get a chance. After all, it is plausible for them to apply the same logic to us in the event that they suspect we are a malevolent civilization; even if they were to assume we are indeed benevolent, they would nevertheless consider the possibility of us suspecting them as malevolent, which would give them a sufficient reason to destroy us to ensure their survival. To break this “<a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/48638053">chain of suspicion</a>” between any two civilizations (or among multiple civilizations), the dark forest hypothesis claims that, following natural selection, only one civilization will prevail should a sound be heard in the universe.</p> <p>While we may know nothing about the moral behavior of extraterrestrial intelligence, it does not hurt to formulate some bold ideas about their nature using our own civilization as a reference. To this date, it would be an overstatement to say our civilization is at peace given our past history and the ongoing international and domestic tensions that are due to our intolerance of others’ race, sexual orientation, political affiliation, religious belief, socioeconomic status, etc., which are causes that would, in theory, escalate into the self-destruction of mankind as technology continues to rapidly progress while our moral compass remains stagnant in the long-run. For an extraterrestrial civilization with an even greater technological capability than us, the fact that they have yet to self-destruct implies that they must have learned to co-exist with one another peacefully in their evolutionary trajectory, such that their sense of morality is of similar magnitude as their technological development. As a matter of fact, a civilization’s societal progress toward peace ought to be assessed on the grounds of their collective moral development in lieu of their level of science and technology since peace can be attained in various ways, some of which are rather unethical. For example, peace can be established in a civilization that is under a 1984-inspired totalitarian regime in which the subjects are controlled by the ruling dictator through mind-controlling technology. Thus, a civilization that is effectively experiencing a moral stagnancy or decline is invariably prone to self-destruction, whereas a highly developed civilization is likely to continue to exist for prolonged periods of time (unless they are destroyed by external factors) as they are guided by strong moral principles.<d-footnote>One other possibility is for a civilization to have a high level of moral development but a low level of technological development; of course, such civilizations would not be vulnerable to self-destruction.</d-footnote> The latter proposition is quite reassuring for us if aliens were to ever visit Earth, in which case they are unlikely to pose as a threat as opposed to the Trisolarans, and albeit this argument is made on the basis of probability and is not self-evident in the least, it offers one possible objection to the dark forest hypothesis so as to make the desolate universe appear more tolerable and humane.</p> <p>Perhaps our desperate search for intelligent life in the universe may serve as a humble reminder to urge ourselves to love one another and cherish our differences for the betterment of humanity down the road. Whether or not we are alone in this vast universe, all that we need to know is the simple fact that our continual existence is a testament to our curiosity and perseverance as we mark our footprints in the history of the universe. Oh, and one last thing, and perhaps this is something that we should all be reminded of from time to time: “Contemplate the marvel that is existence, and rejoice that [we] are able to do so.”<d-footnote>This is one of the concluding remarks from Chiang's short story as mentioned herein.</d-footnote></p> <p><em>Note:</em> Thumbnail Image Source: <a href="https://what-if.xkcd.com/47/">xkcd</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kelvin Chen</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plausible hypotheses elucidating the Fermi paradox and our solitude.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prol. Things That I Find Interesting Outside of Neuroscience</title><link href="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2023/me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prol. Things That I Find Interesting Outside of Neuroscience"/><published>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2023/me</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://k9chen.github.io/blog/2023/me/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="romance-dawn">Romance Dawn</h2> <p>There was a time during high school where my history teacher asked the class on our thoughts regarding the greatest invention in history. The light bulb and the World Wide Web were among some of the more common responses, and while I do see the value and impact of such inventions in propelling societies forward and changing the human condition, my mind had wandered somewhere else entirely.</p> <p>“What are your thoughts?” my teacher finally asked me; I was the last person to be called on.</p> <p>Without much reluctance, I bluntly said, “Calculus.”</p> <p>Immediately following my remark, my peers looked at me in disbelief, thinking that they must have misheard what I had said. My rationale lies in that since the Scientific Revolution, calculus have enabled us to understand the dynamics of the natural world via extensions to complex analysis, probability theory, tensor calculus, etc. with myriad real-world applications from medicine to engineering, such that it is used in ways that perhaps neither Isaac Newton nor Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz could have possibly imagined when they first conceived it.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <img src="/assets/img/meme.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="auto" height="auto" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A math meme from the internet (<a href="https://math.stackexchange.com/questions/4601394/understanding-a-math-meme">Image Source</a>). </div> <p>Yet in retrospect, it seems that my peers did not have the same interpretation toward calculus as what I had in mind; after all, calculus is often synonymous with dread or agony for those who are not interested in mathematics. While our answers were nowhere near what my history teacher was hoping to hear, i.e. Johannes Gutenberg’s printing press, it did made me realize that there is an underlying sense of interpersonal epistemological dissonance between myself and others, whereby there is a contradiction in the perceived value of knowledge and its nature. Thus, it dawned upon me that the problem, of note, stems from the ways with which knowledge is mentally represented in the public consciousness and the emotional connotations that are associated with individual knowledge claims.</p> <p>As an aspiring academic invested in research and teaching, I often find myself being intrigued by many disparate things beyond the realm of my own area of research, i.e. translational neuroscience, including but are not limited to cosmology, quantum physics, pure mathematics, game theory, philosophy, literature, artificial intelligence, and their relations with one another, if any exist. Indeed, perhaps it is my diverse set of interests that originally drew me to something as interdisciplinary as neuroscience, where I could discover its intricate connections with other (un)related ideas and concepts.</p> <p>Sadly, it is not within my power to study all of these things in-depth in the course of one’s lifetime, for I am not a Renaissance man like da Vinci by any means. Nevertheless, having a layman’s understanding of the said topics is sufficient to stimulate and engage my mind in the domains of unacquired knowledge insofar as challenging my present understanding and perception with respect to the natural world. Considering the volume of intellectual knowledge that exists since the inception of time, this blog is a tabula rasa for recording them in the Lockean sense, even if it is just an infinitesimal amount.</p> <p>It is also worthwhile to mention Tim Urban, who writes the blog <a href="https://waitbutwhy.com/">Wait But Why</a>, as a source of inspiration in subconsciously compelling me to explore the fine line between what we do know and what we do not know about the world, allowing me to appreciate the ingenuity of mankind through my own narratives. For these reasons, in an attempt to return to the initial question, it is my firm conviction that the human mind, from which knowledge is derived, is the greatest invention in history (the Dualist might come after me for making the bold assertion that the mind is invented, so I will abruptly end the post here).<d-footnote>See Richard Rorty's book Philosophy and the Mirror of Nature for a detailed discourse on the mind as an invention; as for counterarguments, Thomas Nagel's essay What Is It Like to Be a Bat? offers one such example.</d-footnote></p> <p><em>Note:</em> Thumbnail Image Source: <a href="https://xkcd.com/683/">xkcd</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kelvin Chen</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An utterly unnecessary and uninspiring explanation for why this blog exist.]]></summary></entry></feed>